creativelive.com 2015-06-23

# Privacy Policy | CreativeLive - Learn. Be Inspired.

CreativeLive, Inc. (“CL”) has created this privacy policy to inform you about our how we treat various pieces of information you provide. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for the www.creativelive.com website. 

**Collection of Data/Contact Information/Financial Information**

**IP Address, Diagnostics and Cookies**

We use your internet protocol address and diagnostic information to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our website. We also use your internet protocol address to help identify you and your shopping cart. 

Our website places “cookies” on your computer’s hard drive through your web browsers to keep track of your identity for the purposes of saving your shopping cart and saving your logged-in state so that you do not have to log in each time you visit our website. “Cookies” allow our website to recognize your computer when you access the website. If you would like to prevent the placement of cookies on your computer, or remove cookies from your computer, please access the “Help” portion of your browser or contact your browser provider. Please be advised that if you block or remove cookies from your computer, the website will not recognize your computer and you may not have access to all portions of the website. 

**Contact Information/Financial Information**

Our website’s registration and order forms require users to provide us with contact information to establish membership accounts and purchase services and products. CL collects each user’s name, user ID, address, city, state, postal code, telephone number, IP address and e-mail address. CL uses this information to contact the user regarding purchases, orders and administrative matters (such as reminders regarding the start time/date for an instructional program you chose to attend). New users must opt in to receive commercial communications and may opt out of receiving future commercial communications at any time (see “Anti-Spam Policy/Opt-out Choice” below). CL gathers only user information that is needed to administer its business and enhance and improve its services and products. 

CL also collects and stores information and content you provide to us for your user profile, which is publicly visible to other users of the website. Your username and profile image will be displayed next to your discussion forum posts, comments to our blog, course reviews, and other content that you post or upload to public areas of our website. Examples of information you can provide for your profile are name, brief biography, hobbies and interests, and one or more links to your personal website(s). You can also upload a photo or elect to use your Facebook profile picture, Twitter avatar image, or Gravatar image as your profile picture on our website. If you elect one of these options, you give us permission to access your Facebook, Twitter, or Gravatar account, as the case may be, solely for purposes of displaying your Facebook profile picture, your Twitter avatar image, or your Gravatar profile image as part of your profile on the website. If you do not want your personal information or photo to be visible to other users of the website, do not upload such information or photo to your profile. You can delete or modify the contents of your profile at any time or select an anonymous image for your comments on the site. 

CL does not rent, sell or exchange user information, and generally restricts access to user information to qualified CL employees and agents. 

CL may transmit user information to third-party vendors that provide products or services enabling CL to administer its website, its business and operations or related services. 

CL will make commercially reasonable efforts to disclose when we are transmitting your information to a vendor and provide links to the vendor's policies concerning the use of your information. 

CL uses [Mollom](https://mollom.com/), a service to help identify and eliminate spam and unauthorized posts to the CL blog, forum, reviews and comment systems. The terms of the [Mollom Web Service Privacy Policy](https://mollom.com/web-service-privacy-policy) are available [here](https://mollom.com/web-service-privacy-policy). 

From time to time CL uses [OfferPop, Inc.](https://offerpop.com/), software and web services to run marketing campaigns including but not limited to ads, promotions, and contests. The terms of the [OfferPop Web sites Privacy Policy](https://offerpop.com/privacy-policy.html) are available [here](https://offerpop.com/privacy-policy.html). 

CL may transmit a customer’s credit card data only to the appropriate credit card company and/or credit card payment processing company. CL does not store the financial information entered by users, such as credit card numbers and related financial account information. The financial information is only used to bill the user for products and services. 

CL may disclose a user’s contact or financial information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such disclosure is necessary to comply with an order of a court or government authority, or a subpoena. CL may also disclose a user’s contact or financial information in the good-faith belief that such disclosure is necessary to protect CL or the website, or enforce the applicable Terms and Conditions, in conjunction with an investigation or legal, equitable or administrative action or proceeding. 

CL may collect information on the services and products viewed by you on the website. CL may use this information to customize your experience and suggest and offer you products according to your preferences. CL may use this information to identify patterns and trends of use, but will only release or publish any such information in a manner that preserves your anonymity. 

CL may transfer part or all of your information in the case of a merger, acquisition, bankruptcy, or other sale of all or a portion of CL’s assets or stock. 

**Links to Other Websites**

Any CL website may contain links to other websites. CL is not responsible for the privacy practices, security practices or the content of such websites. 

**Site Intended for Use by Adults**

This website is intended for use by adults. CL does not knowingly collect or publish any information personally identifying any child under age 18. Children under age 18 should not access this website and should not post any information personally identifying themselves anywhere on the website, such as a chat room, forum, message board and/or news group. 

**Security**

The security of this website and your information is of great importance to CL. This website has commercially reasonable security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of your information under our control, but we make no assurances about our ability to prevent any such loss, misuse or alteration, and we shall have no liability to you or any third party from any loss, misuse or alteration. We do not and cannot represent or warrant that your access to the website is completely secure. 

You should promptly notify CL if your account, user name or password have been lost or stolen. CL will never ask you for your password. If you need a new user name and/or password, CL will generate a new user name through its computers and send the means to set or change your password to your e-mail or postal address. 

**Anti-Spam Policy/Opt-out Choice**

We are committed to providing users of this website with the choice to receive or not receive e-mails and/or other communications from CL. We strive to comply with the CAN-SPAM Act. We only send commercial e-mails to new users who have affirmatively requested or consented to receive e-mails about our services and products. We do not send unsolicited commercial e-mails, buy or sell e-mail lists, or use purchased or harvested e-mail lists. We offer commercial e-mail recipients the opportunity to opt-out of further communications in every e-mail. If you would like to opt-outof receiving further communications, you may opt-out at any time though the membership settings in your Membership Profile, or contact us at [support@creativelive.com](mailto:support@creativelive.com). 

Once we receive your opt-out request, please allow 48 hours for us to comply with it.  
Please note that we may not include opt-out information in non-commercial e-mails (i.e., e-mails concerning your order, the website’s terms and conditions of use, etc.). If you have questions or concerns regarding a non-commercial e-mail, please contact us at [support@creativelive.com](mailto:support@creativelive.com) or the physical postal address below. Please allow two business days for us to respond to your e-mail. 

**Modification of Contact Information and/or Financial Information**

If you would like to modify your contact and/or financial information on our database, please log onto your account by clicking the “Login” link on the website. Once logged on, click on the “My Account” link and the “Edit Contact Info” link. You will be able to edit your contact and financial information on the “Edit Contact Info” page. If you have any questions or concerns, or would like to remove or modify your information offline, please contact using one of the following modes:  
E-mail: [support@creativelive.com](mailto:support@creativelive.com)  
Address:  
757 Thomas Street  
Seattle, WA 98109  
Telephone: (206) 403-1395 

**Changes to the Privacy Policy**

CL may change this privacy policy from time to time in its sole and absolute discretion. Please check this website regularly for changes. Substantive revisions to this privacy policy shall apply only prospectively. 

**Contacting**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of CL or your dealings with this website, please contact our customer service department using one of the following modes:  
E-mail: [support@creativelive.com](mailto:support@creativelive.com)  
Address:  
757 Thomas Street  
Seattle, WA 98109  
Telephone: (206) 403-1395 

**User Profiles**

You may create a user profile on the CL website by going to www.creativelive.com/settings/profile. This user profile allows your to participate in the CL online community. Once you have created a user profile, we expect you to use good judgement when using and accessing your user profile. Information and materials posted on or through your user profile are no longer private, and are subject to all the conditions of both our then-current Terms of Use and this Privacy Policy. Because user profiles are an integral part of the CL community experience, CL may, at its sole discretion, permanently or temporarily suspend, block, delete or terminate all or portions of your user profile if you violate or breach the CL Terms of Use or this Privacy Policy. 

**EFFECTIVE DATE: Oct 7, 2012**
